EMILY "LEMONY" DREW LATHAM

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



615-495-4823



www.linkedin.com/in/lemony-web-dev



lemonywebdev@gmail.com



https://github.com/EmilyLemonyDrewL

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | HTML | React | CSS | Git/Github | Python | SQL | Django | Firebase

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Certificate, Software Developer Bootcamp

April 2023 - September 2024

Intensive part-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. The final half of the program are executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in JavaScript, as well as in the React framework
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Solution Design: white-boarding and wireframes
- Leveraged Django for creating and editing servergenerated web applications
- Created RESTful API's with Django REST framework
- Retrieved and stored database information with SQLite
- Practiced testing with Python's unit test framework

PROFILE

Pupil of Nashville Software School, primed and prepared to jump into a career in software development! My ardor for art and design has been a constant presence throughout my life. In college, I learned to handle camera equipment within the film department. In recent times, I served as a mock-up artist for a company that specializes in paper product design, including things like gift bags, stationery, children's books, board games, and more! I am inherently detail-oriented, finding immense satisfaction in projects that demand precision, and an accumulation of effort over time.

PROJECTS

Personal HUBERT HERPS (FRONT-END)

Designed for users fond of herping (looking for reptiles and amphibians), this React-based app uses Firebase storage, Google Authentication and has full CRUD. It allows the user to keep a log of what they find, and view the "finds" of other users.

VIEW CODE VIEW DEPLOYED PROJECT

Group ProjectRARE SERVER 2

Social media app that allows the user to make posts, create their own tags, reactions, and categories, interact with other users' posts and follow other users. This app React/Next.js on the Front End, and Django on the Back End.

FRONT END CODE BACK END CODE

Personal VOCAL FRY

Vocal Fry is a full-stack hiring application designed for voice actors and voice over artists to find jobs. It allows some users to build a profile and look for jobs, and allows other users to list and manage jobs.

FRONT END CODE BACK END CODE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

September 2017 - Present THE CLEVER FACTORY MOCK UP ARTIST

Duties include:

- Collaboration with graphic designers to construct product samples
- Frequent use of crafting machinery (heat sealer, heat gun, laminator, book binder, X-ACTO knife, etc.)
- Familiarity with Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, and the Cricut design space

A job description from one of our online applications:

"Familiarity with many types of crafts/art mediums is necessary. Please note that you will get a little messy sometimes. Those who hate glitter need not apply!"

August 2016 - June 2017

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN MISSISSIPPI STUDENT WORKER (STUDENT SERVICES OFFICE)

Duties include:

- Assisting students with online forms such as graduate applications, or change of name/address forms.
- Updating the weekly E-newsletter
- Photographing and printing student IDs
- Preparing for on-campus events by hanging flyers, decorating, or whatever else was needed.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

CERTIFICATE, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP 2023 - PRESENT

MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

VIDEO PRODUCTION 2014-2015

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN MISSISSIPPI

FILM 2016 - 2017

VOLUNTEER STATE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

RADIO BROADCASTING 2014